# **JASON SWEENEY**

Web Developer and Instructor

Brisbane, Australia

github.com/jsnswny

+61 406 997 441

in/jsnswny

jsnswny@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Driven and innovative individual with a first-class honours degree in Computer Science. Successfully developed and launched a SaaS product which earned an Innovation Award. Transitioned from two years of part-time web development experience to an instructor role at a digital skills academy, furthering my communication, technical, and leadership skills. My passion for technology and entrepreneurial spirit allow me to approach problems from a unique perspective.

#### SKILLS

#### Languages:

Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, PHP, SQL

#### Frameworks/Technologies:

React, Django, Redis, PostgreSQL, Spring Boot, React Native, MongoDB, Next.js, D3.js, Docker, Figma

#### Core Skills:

Adaptability, Creativity, Problem-Solving, Leadership, Team Working, Design Thinking, Strong Communication

#### **EDUCATION** -

#### 2019 - 2023 **BSc Computer Science (First-Class Honours)**

Heriot-Watt University, Edinburgh

· Coursework: Data Structures & Algorithms, Data Mining & Machine Learning, Statistical Modelling & Analysis, Data Visualisation, Spoken Language Processing, Software Engineering

#### EXPERIENCE -

5/2023 - Present Bartender

Verona Fresh Italian, Birtinya

- · Delivered drinks quickly and efficiently in a fast-paced bar setting.
- · Applied my mixology knowledge to craft new cocktails for our menu.

## 12/2023 - 4/2024 Junior Sommelier

Olivine Wine Bar, Melbourne

· Learned wine pouring techniques and vocabulary to provide a high level of service at a hatted venue.

#### 9/2022 - 11/2023 **Software Instructor**

CodeClan, Scotland

- Led a 16-week intensive cohort of 20+ students in Python (Flask), JavaScript (Express/React/MongoDB), and Java (Spring Boot) courses, adapting content to suit my teaching style.
- Delivered a 10-week Web Development course on building a Django web app.
- · Instructed various short courses covering data analysis, web development, and Python for beginners.
- · Collaborated with team members to successfully achieve course objectives.

#### 9/2020 - 9/2022 Web Developer (Part-time)

Web Integrations LTD, Scotland

- · Contributed to the development and maintenance of websites using PHP-based frameworks (WordPress, SilverStripe, CraftCMS) for both new projects and existing clients' sites.
- · Maintained consistent communication with the rest of the team through Slack to ensure project deadlines were being met.
- · Worked with designers to outline requirements needed for the development of website projects.
- · Communicated with clients to discuss improvements and assist with changes to their websites.

## **PROJECTS**

2022 - 2023

A mobile app to allow users to match with professionals based on programming languages and interests.

- · Filtered and cleaned a dataset of 10M GitHub users to produce a subset of data (168k) that could be used to build and test a hybrid recommender system
- Implemented a redis database to store similarity matrices which improved recommendation time by 66%, and to manage real-time communication for the messaging interface
- · Designed a high-fidelity prototype in Figma, and built a mobile and web interface using Next.js/TypeScript/React Native, and the REST API using Django Rest Framework

#### 2021 - 2022

readysetrota

GitHub

A shift management application that I built for the hospitality industry to be affordable and intuitive.

- · Submitted a business plan and delivered a 3-minute pitch for an Innovation Challenge held by my university, successfully winning the Innovation Award and receiving £8k of funding
- · Built the frontend using React/Redux to develop a complex user interface for viewing and publishing shifts, and a REST API using Django Rest Framework
- · Implemented a per-seat pricing model using Stripe